<document>
    <properties>
        <title>Apache Synapse - Mediators Catalog</title>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="Contents">
            <ul>
                <li><a href="#Intro">Introduction</a></li>
                <li><a href="#Categories">Mediator Categories</a></li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section name="Introduction" id="Intro">
            <p>
                Mediator is the basic message processing unit in Synapse. A mediator takes an
                input message, carries out some processing on it, and provides an output message.
                Mediators can be linked up and arranged into chains to implement complex message
                flows (sequences). Mediators can manipulate message content (payload), properties,
                headers and if needed can also execute additional tasks such as database lookup,
                service invocation and script execution.
            </p>
            <p>
                Apache Synapse ships with an array of useful mediators that can be used out of the
                box to implement message flows, services and integration patterns. Rest of this
                article describes these mediators in detail, along with their use cases and
                configuration syntax.
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="Mediator Categories" id="Categories">
            <p>
                Built-in mediators of Synapse can be classified into several groups depending
                on the nature of their functionality and use cases.
            </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    Core mediators - Utility mediators that are useful in a variety of scenarios
                </li>
                <li>
                    Filter mediators - Mediators used to filter out messages
                </li>
                <li>
                    Transform mediators - Mediators used to transform message content, headers and
                    attributes
                </li>
                <li>
                    Extension mediators - Mediators used to extend the Synapse mediation engine by
                    plugging in custom developed code
                </li>
                <li>
                    Advanced mediators - Mediators used to implement advanced integration scenarios
                    and patterns
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>